# **MUHAMAD UBAYDILLAH**

WEB DEVELOPER

ubaydillah90@protonmail.com

0851-6255-9660

Tangerang, Indonesia.

# **Profile Summary**

Hello I am Muhamad Ubaydillah, I am currently studying Informatics Engineering at Esa Unggul University. I have work experience in the field of web development for 2 years 11 months, the technologies that I usually use to create websites include: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Reactjs, TailwindCSS, MySQL, Mongodb and Nodejs. And currently I am exploring the Laravel Framework because I recently learned it and I am very excited about using Laravel to create front-end and backend websites.

# **Work Experience**

## Web Developer & Font Developer - Creative Corner Studio

Feb 2021 - Jan 2024

- Implement UI Web Design into a website using technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, TailwindCSS, ReactJS, Ionic and Wordpress.
- Handling websites & do minor updates that are already live in production.
- Setup domain and hosting at niagahoster.
- Setup domain and wordpress installation process.
- Deploy the website using cpanel, Vercel and Netlify.
- Transform the letter design to a suitable font format, such as TTF or OTF.
- Conduct extensive testing to ensure proper functionality and visual quality of each character in the font.
- Uploading fonts that have been coded and previewed are ready to several websites such as Creative Market and Envanto

# Web Developer - PT. Sarana Daya Semesta

Sep 2021 - Jan 2024

- Building responsive and visually appealing user interfaces (UI) using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Wordpress.
- Do minor updates on websites that are already live.
- Setup domain and hosting at niagahoster.
- Implementing responsive layouts to support a good user experience across devices.

#### Front-end Developer - Rumatani

Feb 2021 - Sep 2021

- Develop a dynamic and visually engaging website, incorporating a variety of animations to enhance the user experience.
- Develop a Front-end Mobile App using Ionic for user can buy veggetable and needs.
- Develop Landing Page Rumatani with Reactis and CSS.
- Compress Image assets for rendering speed on website.
- Scrapping data using Google map Scrapper

#### **Education**

## **Esa Unggul University**

Sep 2020 - Current

Informatics Engineering focuses on Web Programming

# SMK Yappika Legok

Jul 2015 - Jun 2018

Majoring in Multimedia and focusing on making public service announcements.

Active in Paskibra activities and was Paskibra in Legok sub-district in 2016.

#### The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp

Aug 2019 - Des 2019

- This certificate above verifies that Muhamad Ubaydillah successfully completed the course The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp on 12/20/2019 as taught by Dr. Angela Yu on Udemy.
- https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-Q0E1UHVO/

## Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More!

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

- This certificate above verifies that Muhamad Ubaydillah successfully completed the course Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More! on 10/31/2019 as taught by Jonas Schmedtmann on Udemy.
- https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-Q0E1UHVO/

# Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2024

Nov 2019 - June 2020

- This certificate above verifies that Muhamad Ubaydillah successfully completed the course Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2024 on 06/08/2020 as taught by Jonas Schmedtmann on Udemy.
- https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-Q0E1UHVO/

# The Complete React Developer Course (w/ Hooks and Redux)

*Jun 2020 - Dec 2020* 

- This certificate above verifies that Muhamad Ubaydillah successfully completed the course The Complete React Developer Course (w/ Hooks and Redux) on 12/29/2020 as taught by Andrew Mead on Udemy.
- https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-494457bd-34f0-4563-9f3cef4d756315d3/

## **Professional Skill**

#### **Soft Skill**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Node.js, PHP
- Mongodb, MySQL
- ReactJs, NextJs, Laravel
- SCSS, TailwinCSS, Bootstrap
- Wordpress

- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Responsibility
- Team Work

#### Social Media & Portofolio

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhamad-ubaydillah-9819b3165/
- https://github.com/ubaydillah77
- https://ubay-portofolio.vercel.app/

#### Languages

- Bahasa Indonesia
- English